Hello, programmer. Welcome back to today's another new tutorial topic. So today here, I'm going to
explore the three powerful aggregate function in the post grid SQL, the count sum average and
this function allows us to perform the calculation in the state of data, such as counting the number
of rows, sum in up the values and calculating the average. Okay. So now let's start and now here
I'll explore for some example and help us gain insight into our data by summarizing the
information in the meaningful way. Okay. So first of all, starting point here, the counting
the number of rows. Okay. So now just do in first of all here, I can try select and now then
we can use the first with the count function. Okay. And perfectly define the count function
and next up here, I can choose from the table just like the count employee stable. Okay.
So first using the count function to count the number of rows in the employee stable. Okay.
And use the asterisk in the count all rows. Okay. So now just select all and then perfectly execute
and you can see the confirmation message, successful and the post grid SQL going to make the
total number of templates as the result of five. Okay. So this is perfectly working the count
function. Okay. Next step here, I can use for calculating the total sum. Okay. So here, I can use
for the sum function and calculate the total salary from the salary of the employee sales. Okay.
So select and just remove this count and apply for the sum and define for the salary call. Okay.
Now this on perfect and then execute and you can see the this the print for here, the total
salary 22 or 25,000 total summary for successful and the post grid will return the total sum of
salaries of the sale. Okay. And I hope you perfectly understand this the total sum of the salaries.
And this is the complete diagram. Next step here, I can use the calculating the average
salary. Okay. So now here, going to use the average function to calculate the average salary
from the salary column of the employee stable. So now here simply check for the sum and here
like the Fij and this as resident now, just select and execute and you can see here these average
salary for here 45,000. Okay. So I hope you perfectly understand here this operation is successful
and it will most price the return for the average salary as the result says. Okay. So I hope
you understand. And now we are going to edit the function over the condition. So now here,
apply the free function and with the condition. So again, type the count and
then type for here term. Okay. And also here, just use for the sum, then here, I can use the
salary and also use the average of the salary. And here, I'm going to apply for the word
used in the department from is equal to. So now I can choose for the department of IT. Okay.
So now it is perfectly used the free function and calculate the total salary and average salary
but only the employee in the IT department. Okay. So now first of all, here I can select and execute
and you can see here the employee's name now, apply and one and result is 3,000, 30,000 and also
here the 30,000. So it will count on then sum and the average. Okay. And here, complete
the suppression and the post grid will return the these aggregated values from the
IT department employees for the result. So here, in this session is completely done.
And here, I have perfectly using the count sum and the average function, the post grid SQL.
Oh, it's some practical example. Okay. So I hope you found this tutorial helpful. So stay tuned for
more post grid SQL tips and tricks. So thank you for watching.